

Salvador Olvera Nava

Jr. Full Stack Developer

@ salvador.olvera@outlook.com

salvador-olvera-n

Salvador-ON

salvador-on.github.io

Download Resume

CAREER SUMMARY

Full-Stack Remote Software Developer with a passion for coding and creating web applications with intuitive user experiences, UI effects, and responsive design. I have been extensively involved in developing web applications such as front-end user interface, and back-end database management. I have experience working with remote teams, and advanced proficiencies in HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, Ruby, Ruby on Rail, and React/Redux.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jr Full-Stack Developer.

Microverse Web Development Program - Remote.

2020

Honed my remote working skills, Working remotely over 1000 hours with colleagues from other parts of the world.

Built over 30 projects during the program, showing my learned Front-end and Back-end skills.

Developed my testing skills using RSpec/Capybara on Ruby on Rails and Jest on JavaScript to create unit and integration test. Mentored new students, helping and guiding them through the program. Reviewed and tested their codes and giving feedback to improve it. And helping them to understand some concepts.

Mentored new students, helping and guiding them through the program. Reviewed and tested their codes and giving feedback to improve it. And helping them to understand some concepts.

Technologies used:

Ruby on Rails React/Redux

JavaScript Webpack HTML5/CSS3/SASS SQL Adobe CS

Chief Operating Officer.

2016 - 2019

Supervised and lead the daily operations of the company including manufacturing operations, engineering, purchase, human resources, and administration.

Established the key performance indicators to control and monitor production effectiveness.

Developed the annual strategic plan to improve the key performance indicators. Improving production efficiency by 15%.

Managed the logistics entry of the company to the Stratasys Global Manufacturing Network. From the development of the start plan of the new production lines to the startup, and lead the daily manufacturing operations.

Ensured proper management of resources, distribution of goods and services to customers, and supply chain.

Technologies used:

Adobe CS Ganttic Python) Google Spreadsheets **Zapier JotForm** Asana

Adittive Manufacture Chief Officer.

2015 - 2016

Developed and implemented a quality validation system for the manufactured items. Helping to avoid sending defective items.

Developed and implemented a Manufacturing Execution System. Helping the company to track and capture data, of the processes and outcomes of the manufacturing process.

Planned and executed daily production schedules, supervised, coordinated, and evaluated Human Resources to ensure daily production.

Standardized the manufacturing operations processes including cad file preparations, manufacturing, post-treatments, maintenance, and shipments.

Technologies used:

Embedded Systems Python Google Spreadsheets Zapier **JotForm** Asana Solidworks / Inventor

Jr Engineer.

2014 - 2015

Researched and developed the post-treatments. Helping to improve the quality of the pieces.

Developed and implemented tools and jigs, with the aim of reducing scrap and ensuring product quality and increasing the safety of the processes.

Researched and developed the improvement of the software parameters and hardware on the additive manufacturing equipment. Improving the visual quality of the pieces, reducing scrap by 10%, and post-treatment times by 15%.

Technologies used:

Arduino

Raspberry Pi

Python)

Google Spreadsheets

Solidworks / Inventor

SKILLS & TOOLS

Frontend

HTML/CSS/SASS

Bootstrap

React

JavaScript

Backend

Ruby/Rails

Skills

Tridi Mx.

SQL

Project Management

Lean Manufacturing

Continual Improvement Process

Problem Solving Code Review Git Linux Adobe CS

Wireframing **Unit Testing Teamwork** Creativity

Pair Programming Proactivity

Full-Stack Developer.

EDUCATION

Microverse Web Development Program. 2020

Mechatronic Engineering.

Universidad del Valle de México. 2011 - 2015

Manager Mentor.

Harvard Business School. 2012

Continuous Process Automatization.

Festo.

2012

Solidworks CSWA.

Solidworks.

2012

Tridi Mx.

Tridi Mx.

AWARDS

Laureate Award for **Excellence in Robotic Engineering**

Team leader of Mexico team and finalist at the Laureate Award for Excellence in Robotics Engineering, Second edition, 2015.

LANGUAGE

Spanish (Native)

English (Professional)